# NISHANT SALHOTRA

SOFTWARE ENGINEER \$\cup +91 8130816709\$

#### • DETAILS •

+91 8130816709 nsalhotrawork@gmail.com

• LINKS •

HackerRank

**LinkedIn** 

<u>Github</u>

**Twitter** 

SKILLS

TypeScript

JavaScript

React

Node.js

**React Native** 

Git

GraphQL

HTML & CSS

**AWS** 

Infrastructure

SQL

• LANGUAGES •

English

Hindi

Japanese

## PROFILE

Creative and analytical Software Engineer with over 8 years of experience in web and mobile application development, specializing in the JavaScript/TypeScript ecosystem. Delivered 15+ projects and collaborated with 10+ teams, both remotely and onsite; developed applications reaching millions and consistently earned promotions at the last three companies to roles of increasing responsibility.

#### EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

### Software Engineer | Freelance

November 2023 — Present

Took up freelance work after nearly 7 years of full-time work; helping companies improve business metrics.

- Built a website for an Interior Design startup using React and NextJS, leading to a 300% increase in leads.
- Fixed performance bottlenecks in a React Native app with over 1 million downloads on Google Play Store.
- Directed team mentorship initiatives and implemented advanced code review practices; reviewed engineering workflows to enhance sprint productivity by 20% and decrease bug count by 50%.
- Built features for a React Native app for relative scheduling, finishing the v0 of the application within 5 working days.

#### Senior Software Engineer at LoanCrate, New York City (Remote)

January 2021 — September 2023

As one of the 3 founding engineers, played a major role in building a Loan Origination System, which a major Top-20 private lender in the US adopted.

- Spearheaded the development full-stack features using TypeScript, Node, GraphQL, React, PostgreSQL (Prisma), AWS, and Terraform.
- Led the development of a flexible data model framework for managing highly dynamic data on the client and server.
- Led the development of a complex rules engine for data validation and business logic on the client and the server.
- Delivered the Post-Closing LOS application within the first 4 months of joining. This led to a 210% increase in loan processing efficiency.
- Played a major role as an on-call engineer after going live, maintaining a 100% up-time record.

## Senior Software Engineer at BuddyBoss, Toronto (Remote)

March 2020 — December 2020

The BuddyBoss app is a cross-platform development framework for mobile apps on both Android and iOS with just one code base written in React Native and configured via WordPress.

- As a developer on the platform team, led the development of features like photo album management, bio-metric locking and social media features.
- Quickly became one of the most crucial members of the team. Managed tricky situations like making a major publicly declared deadline by covering for a co-worker who abruptly quit the team.

## Lead Mobile Application Developer at Sportskeeda, Bengaluru

March 2019 — February 2020

Sportskeeda is a big player in sports media and news in India. As the second developer on the iOS app team,

• Developed the app from scratch using React Native and went live within 2 months.

- Managed a team of 4 developers while spearheading the development process and planning sprints.
- Got promoted to be the team lead within 4 months.
- Managed the project end-to-end including the company's app store account and deployments.

#### Software Engineer, Freelance

August 2018 — February 2019

Transitioned to freelance development after previous company pivoted to a coding boot camp model.

- Acquired 4 clients within 6 months by employing LinkedIn connections, crafting compelling cold emails, and showcasing good communication ability.
- Developed a social sporting event management application with a company in Switzerland. Delivered all features before deadlines and got a full-time job offer.
- Developed developed features for a food delivery application for an Indian startup, including ordering modules, Geo-location integration and online payments. As a result, Y-Combinator funded this startup. Received an offer for a full-time role.

## Software Engineer at Pesto Tech, New Delhi

June 2017 — July 2018

Pesto Tech started as a software consulting firm for clients in the US, later pivoting into a coding school for working professionals.

- Developed, delivered and maintained 2 mobile applications using React Native in 9 months.
- Developed features for the website of a big cake company in New York.
- Co-created a comprehensive curriculum for coding boot camps in 2 weeks.
- Gave lectures on React, JavaScript, Git and solved coding questions on stage while answering students' questions.

#### Software Engineer at Dealflow, New Delhi

June 2016 — May 2017

A FinTech startup in the public funding space. Delivered an MVP within 3 months as a React Developer, while attending the final year of college.

# Software Engineer (Intern) at Sopra Steria, Noida

January 2016 — March 2016

Developed and optimized an internal human resource management application, built with vanilla JS and jQuery, leading to a permanent job offer.

# **EDUCATION**

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science, Maharaja Agrasen Institute of Technology January 2013 — January 2017